<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lessons From the Tabletop on Josh Lee on the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lessons-from-the-tabletop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lessons From the Tabletop on Josh Lee on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 14:30:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lessons-from-the-tabletop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Sharing the Narrative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sharing-the-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 14:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sharing-the-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, you’re probably already familiar with Critical Role — By far one of the most popular live streams of tabletop roleplaying. The show’s GM, Matt Mercer, has several famous lines, but perhaps the most famous is “How do you want to do this?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For context, Matt will ask this of his players when they have delivered the killing blow to a major opponent. What the simple phrase communicates to the player is: “By the rules of the game, the enemy is defeated — you get to narratively describe how it happens.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Know Your Domain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rpg-lessons-domain-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 12:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rpg-lessons-domain-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is Part III in my series&lt;/em&gt; Lessons from the Tabletop: Things I’ve learned about project management from Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons*. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/project-management-rpg-lessons/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read Part I&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt;.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many dungeon masters fall victim to the trap of over-preparation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spending a lot of time preparing a specific plan for a game can make it difficult to let go of that plan (as I wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt;). One might conclude that planning is a waste of time. As an absolute, this could not be more wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 05:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is part II in my series&lt;/em&gt; Lessons from the Tabletop: Things I’ve learned about project management from Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons*. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/project-management-rpg-lessons/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read Part I here&lt;/a&gt;.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Game masters also have an inside joke: “No plot survives contact with the players.” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When I attempt to drive the plot, dictate the player options and the pacing, the players begin to disengage. The same thing happens on teams when a leader begins to white-knuckle the steering wheel. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Things I&#39;ve Learned about Project Management from Dungeons &amp; Dragons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project-management-rpg-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 05:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project-management-rpg-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;For the past year or so, I’ve been getting together with a group of friends once a week to play Dungeons and Dragons. The popular role-playing game from the ‘70s has enjoyed something of a resurgence in the last few years. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In the game, 4-6 players act as characters that they create using randomized dice rolls. One player, the game master, tells the other players about the world and what they see. The players respond by saying what they’d like their characters to do, and the game master will tell them if they need to roll any dice to determine the outcome of the attempted action. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
