<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>For Developers on Josh Lee on the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/for-developers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in For Developers on Josh Lee on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 14:30:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/for-developers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Sharing the Narrative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sharing-the-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 14:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sharing-the-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, you’re probably already familiar with Critical Role — By far one of the most popular live streams of tabletop roleplaying. The show’s GM, Matt Mercer, has several famous lines, but perhaps the most famous is “How do you want to do this?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For context, Matt will ask this of his players when they have delivered the killing blow to a major opponent. What the simple phrase communicates to the player is: “By the rules of the game, the enemy is defeated — you get to narratively describe how it happens.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Developer&#39;s Guide to WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/developers-guide-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 08:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/developers-guide-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the most popular CMS on the planet: &lt;em&gt;WordPress&lt;/em&gt;. If you’re a developer inexperienced with WordPress, some of what you’re about to read will surely make you cringe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a senior engineer who wants to understand the architecture of WordPress, then this guide is for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So let’s pull back the curtain and take a look at some of the architecture in WordPress:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;posts--one-table-to-rule-them-all&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;strong&gt;Posts — One Table to Rule Them All&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#posts--one-table-to-rule-them-all&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordPress was initially built for blogging, and so its core model is called the post. In WordPress, almost everything is a post. The built-in post types besides &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; (blog posts) are: &lt;code&gt;page&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;attachment&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;link&lt;/code&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Know Your Domain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rpg-lessons-domain-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 12:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rpg-lessons-domain-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is Part III in my series&lt;/em&gt; Lessons from the Tabletop: Things I’ve learned about project management from Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons*. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/project-management-rpg-lessons/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read Part I&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt;.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many dungeon masters fall victim to the trap of over-preparation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spending a lot of time preparing a specific plan for a game can make it difficult to let go of that plan (as I wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt;). One might conclude that planning is a waste of time. As an absolute, this could not be more wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using git on Small Teams: Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/using-git-on-teams-vcs-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 15:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/using-git-on-teams-vcs-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of ways to use git to collaborate with other developers. I’ve found the following principles to be useful for keeping my sanity when working with git. My experience has mostly been with small teams of two to six developers, but these principles may apply to any size team. Of course, “best practices” are elusive, and the following is just my established method.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;commandments&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Commandments:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#commandments&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not commit vendor code.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not commit compiled code.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not commit commented-out code — just delete it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make small commits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explain the why, not the what, in your commit message.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a new branch for every task / small feature / bug fix.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rebase instead of merge to resolve conflicts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use pull requests. Get reviews.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not commit or push directly to the master branch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploy from the master branch to staging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;master-branch-only-contains-reviewed-code-merged-via-pr&#34;&gt;&#xA;  “Master” branch only contains reviewed code, merged via PR&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#master-branch-only-contains-reviewed-code-merged-via-pr&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When an entire QA department is not available, the best QA gains can be had by ensuring every single line of code is seen by at least 2 developers before being merged into the master branch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 05:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons-tabletop-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is part II in my series&lt;/em&gt; Lessons from the Tabletop: Things I’ve learned about project management from Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons*. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamlee.com/project-management-rpg-lessons/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read Part I here&lt;/a&gt;.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Game masters also have an inside joke: “No plot survives contact with the players.” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When I attempt to drive the plot, dictate the player options and the pacing, the players begin to disengage. The same thing happens on teams when a leader begins to white-knuckle the steering wheel. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Tabletop: Things I&#39;ve Learned about Project Management from Dungeons &amp; Dragons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project-management-rpg-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 05:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project-management-rpg-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;For the past year or so, I’ve been getting together with a group of friends once a week to play Dungeons and Dragons. The popular role-playing game from the ‘70s has enjoyed something of a resurgence in the last few years. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In the game, 4-6 players act as characters that they create using randomized dice rolls. One player, the game master, tells the other players about the world and what they see. The players respond by saying what they’d like their characters to do, and the game master will tell them if they need to roll any dice to determine the outcome of the attempted action. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
